Now that we know what git is, um the
question you may have is what is GitHub?
Um well, when you are doing git version
control, you'll remember that those
files are stored on your computer. So,
it keeps track in a little hidden folder
called.git. Um and it keeps track of
every change you made to your file. The
problem becomes if something happens to
your computer, all of the changes and
all of those track changes were on your
computer and they're gone. So let's say
crazy situation, your computer explodes,
you'll have lost all of your code. So
what GitHub does is it allows you to
store your code in the cloud. And that
way when your computer dies or something
happens to it, everything is still in
the cloud. The other thing GitHub allows
you to do is to collaborate with other
users who are not on the same device as
you. So you can push it your code up
into the cloud. They can access the code
in the cloud, make changes, and push
their code to the cloud. And now it's
all stored where multiple people can
access it. Um, and if a fire happens and
you lose your computer or you drop it
down the stairs or who knows what
happens, um,
your computer, your code is still safe
because it's out in the cloud. Um, and
just to show you what it will look like
when you log in to GitHub, this is what
it looks like when you log into GitHub.
Um, and so I'll pick up further here
when I start describing how you use
GitHub, but just as a definition, GitHub
is a place that stores your code just
somewhere out on the in it.